Your mission: don't die.
Doom: Annihilation is a action, science fiction,
horror film directed by Tony Giglio.
A group of UAC Marines responds to a distress call from a top-secret scientific base on
Phobos, a Martian moon, only to discover it's been overrun by demons.
Joan Dark, played by Amy Manson.
Dr. Bennett Stone, played by Luke Allen-Gale.
Carley, played by Nina Bergman.
Dr. Malcolm Betruger, played by Dominic Mafham.
Captain Hector Savage, played by James Weber Brown.
Sandy Peterson, played by Lorina Kamburova.
Doom: Annihilation is a 2019 American science fiction action
film written and directed by Tony Giglio.
It is a reboot based on id Software's Doom franchise and is
the second live-action film after Doom (2005).
The film stars Amy Manson, Dominic Mafham, Luke Allen-Gale, and Nina Bergman.
In the film, marines battle demon-like creatures in a facility on Phobos, who
have emerged from ancient teleportation devices known as "Gates".
Giglio pitched his idea for a new film to Universal in
2015, but was initially turned down.
The success of the 2016 video game convinced Universal to
proceed and commission a script from Giglio.
The project was announced in April 2018, with principal photography commencing soon
afterward, and ending in June, with additional photography following in early 2019.
id Software publicly iterated that they were not involved with the film since they
had earlier declined an invitation to participate in its production.
Doom: Annihilation was released direct-to-video on October 1, 2019, to mixed
reviews and earned $78,389 (~$96,407 in 2024) in domestic video sales.
The film explores themes of planet mars, hell,
space, demon, based on video game.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.